Guide to the Helen and Kurt Wolff Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1903-1994; Series I; 18.97' (46 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Albert Langen, Georg Müller Verlag GMBH, 1960-63 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Albin Michel (Firm), 1963-89 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1960-82 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Includes photocopy of letter from Knopf to Herbert Mitgang
    - Allen, James Sloan, 1982 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Altenhein, Hans, 1988-93 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1985 Apr 19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - American Center of P.E.N., 1977-89 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Includes draft of manuscript, "The Responsibilities of Translation"
    - American Teilhard de Chardin Association, [ca. 1990-92] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Ames, Evie, 1960-82, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Amis de Georges Simenon, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Anders, Günther, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Andersch, Alfred, 1961-63 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Andre Deutsch Limited, 1967-90 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1984 Nov 22 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Aperture, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1957-75, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29-34)
    - Arndt, Walter, 1959-93, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Arnoldo Mondadori editore, 1963-67 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Artemis Verlag, 1961-62 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Ascoli, Max, 1958-60 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Assouline, Pierre, 1991-93, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Atchley, Dana, 1959-62 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Atlas, 1961-62 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Aubry, Marcel, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1959-72, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - "B" General, 1954-91 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Bach, Susanne, 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Bachem, F. C., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Bachemhaus, 1961-62 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Bachofer, Ludwig, 1954 Dec (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Bailey, Herbert [Smith?], 1982 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Baines, Jocelyn, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Bamm, Peter, 1963 Mar (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Bantam Books (Firm), 1975-76 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Barker, Palmer W., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Barloewen, Constantin von, 1982-90, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Barnes, Christopher J., 1984, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Barth von Wehrenalp, Erwin, 1992 Oct (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Barthelme, Donald
      See: Frisch, Max, Box 7, folder 306
    - Bassani, Giorgio, 1972-73 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Bates, Marston, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Bauch, [Kurt?], 1963 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Bauer, Maria, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Bauer, Wolfgang; Bauer, Annette, 1962-64 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Bawden, Charles R., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Bayerischer Rundfunk, 1962-63 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Baynes, Cary [F.?], 1957-61 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Bechert & Dexel, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Beck Engraving Company, 1954 Dec 22 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Becker, John, 1959-83 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Becker, Kate, 1960-61 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Becker, Lucille Frackman, 1971 Sep 20 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Beidler, Franz W. [(Franz Wilhelm)?], 1958-60 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      Includes copies of letters from Beidler to Hans Karrer and Rascher Verlag
    - Benemann, Maria, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Berbig, Roland, 1991-92 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Berg, A. Scott (Andrew Scott), 1993 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Berger, Yves, 1981, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Berliner Festwochen, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Bermann Fischer, Gottfried, 1966-91 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Bernheim, Alfred
      See: Maraini, Fosco, Box 28, folder 846
    - Bertin, Célia, 1980-93 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      Includes enclosure
    - Beutler, Christian, 1962 Jan (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Bidermanas, Izis, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Biederstein Verlag, 1960-67 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Bihalji-Merin, Oto, 1962-85 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      See also: Jugoslavija, Box 21, folders 651-654
    - Bischof, Walter G., 1961 Apr (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Bjurström, [Carl Gustaf?], 1959-60 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Black Mountain College (Black Mountain, N.C.), 1944 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Blake, Patricia, 1985 Jul 26 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Blanch, Lesley, 1982-83 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Blinn, Jeff, 1972-73 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Blythe, Ronald, 1982-88 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - B'nai B'rith
      See: Oz, Amos, Box 32, folder 984
    - Bollingen Foundation, 1949-69, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 89-92)
      Includes third-party correspondence between Bollingen and Routledge, Hans Karrer, and Jackson Mathews
      See also: Jung, Carl Gustav, Box 21, folder 658, Panofsky, Erwin, Box 32, folder 991; and Sauerländer, Wolfgang, Box 38, folders 1177-1178
    - Bompiani (Firm), 1962-66 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Bonner, Anthony, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1958-82 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Borchers, Elisabeth, 1972 Dec 8 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Born, Jürgen, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Börsenblatt für den deutschen Buchhandel, 1964, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Botsford, Keith
      See: Luke, David, Box 26, folder 793
    - Bouleau, Charles, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 99)
      Includes printed publicity for Bouleau's The Painter's Secret Geometry
    - Boyle, Kay
      See: Johnson, Uwe, Box 19, folder 614
    - Brenan, Gerald, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Brentano's (Firm), 1957 Nov 14 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Broch, Hermann, 1942-48, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102-107)
    - Brod, Max, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Brown, Francis, 1960 Aug 23 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Brownjohn, John, 1983 Nov 7 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Bruckberger, R.-L. (Raymond-Leopold), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Bruna, A. W., 1966-68 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Bryan, Ashley, 1970, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Bryher
      See: Harvill Press, Box 15, folder 484 and Holsaert, James, Box 17, folder 548
    - Buber, Martin, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Buch, Hans Christoph, 1984 Oct 13 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Buchenau, Siegfried, 1961, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Burden, Jean, 1982, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Burns & Oates Ltd., 1960-65 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Burton, Naomi
      See: Curtis Brown, Box 3, folders 175-176 and Doubleday, Box 4, folders 207-208
    - Busch, Adolf, 1945-46 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      Copies of letters to Busch
    - Busch, Frieda, 1943-46, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Busch, Hans, 1985 Mar 4 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Busch, Noel [Fairchild?], 1969 Jun 12 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Butler, Jack
      See: Harington, Donald, Box 13, folder 455
    - "C" General, 1962-91 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - C. Bertelsmann Verlag, 1962-90 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Cairns, Huntington, 1948-59 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Calder, Renate, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Calvino, Italo, 1984, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 127)
      Includes third-party correspondence and enclosures
    - Campbell, Joseph, 1953-80, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Campbell, Maria B., 1981-91 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Campion, Nardi Reeder, 1982-83 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Cane, Melville, 1955-78 (Box 3, Folder 131-133)
    - Caplette, Michele, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Carl Hanser Verlag, 1960-86 (Box 3, Folder 135-138)
    - Carlisle, Henry
      See: Feltrinelli editore, Box 6, folder 274
    - Carter, Richard B. (Richard Burnett), 1982 Oct 18 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Cayrol, Jean, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Chagnon, Napoleon A., 1982-84 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Chandler, Janet Carncross, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Chanticleer Press Inc., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Charney, Ann, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Chatterji, N., 1963 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Chatto & Windus (Firm), [1971?] (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Chisholm, Hugh, 1951, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - The Christian Science Monitor, 1960, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 148)
      Includes copies of poems by Hanns Cibulka
    - Claasen Verlag, 1961-67 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Clark, Kenneth, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Clarke, Gerald, 1971 Nov 3 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - [Coatsworth, Elizabeth Jane?], 1960 Aug 7 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Cohen, Arthur [Allen?], 1979-84 (Box 4, Folder 153)
      Includes copy of letter from Cohen to Carlos Cruz
    - Collier, Peter, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Collins, Frank, 1985 Dec 30 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Collins, Pierre, 1982-84, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Collovedo, Berthe, 1966-67 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Colsman, Cornelia, 1992-94 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Columbia University. Translation Center, 1981-86, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Commentary, 1978 Mar 29 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Commins, Dorothy, 1979-84, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Confiserie Spruengli, 1971-79 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Conroy, Kathryn, 1959-61 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Constable (Firm), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Cosmopolitan Club (New York, N.Y.) (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Coster, Charles Henry; Coster, [Byba?], 1963-68 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Coulter, Douglas, 1986-89, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Couturier, Marie-Alain, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Crenshaw, Mary Ann, 1984 Oct 25 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Crocker, William Charles, 1967-68 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Csicsery-Rónay, István, 1988 Jun 19 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Cudahy, Sheila, 1960-93, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Cürlis, Hans; Cürlis, Peter, 1948-49, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Curschmann, Michael
      See: Princeton University, Box 36, folder 1086
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1958-66 (Box 4, Folder 175-176)
      See also: Doubleday, Box 4, folders 207-208
    - Curtiss, Mina [Kirstein?], 1961 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Curtius, Ernst Robert, 1951-54, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Curtius, Ludwig, 1950 Jun 26 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - "D" General, 1960-82, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Daedalus, 1982 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Daily Telegraph, 1960 Jan (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Dartmouth College, 1990 Nov 26 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - Darton, Longman & Todd Limited, 1960 Jun 20 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Daves, Joan, 1961-88 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - David R. Godine, Publisher, 1979-84 (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - Davis, Liselotte M., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 187)
      Includes manuscript, "Interview with Helen Wolff"
    - Deborah Rogers Ltd., 1967, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - De Lange, N.R.M. (Nicolas Robert Michael), 1986 Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - Delas, Marcel, 1921-23, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 190-192)
      Includes contract
    - De Mendelssohn, Peter, 1987 Jul 17 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Demetz, Peter, 1982-92 (Box 4, Folder 194-195)
      Includes copies of letters from Demetz to C. Bertin-Reich and Ernst Piper
    - De Regniers, Beatrice [Schenk?], 1960 Jul 4 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - Dessi, Giuseppe, 1962 Mar 1 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Deutsches Literaturarchiv (Germany), 1986 Apr 15 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Devaulx, Noël, 1961 Sep 26 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Devena, Mario, 1961-62 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - DeVinney, Russell Norman, 1980-87 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Diogenes Verlag, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Dispersion and Unity, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Dittrich [van Weringh?], Kathinka, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Doderer, Heimito von, 1964-67 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Doring-Smirnov, Johanna Renate, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Doubleday and Company, 1959-84, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 207-208)
      See also: Curtis Brown, Box 4, folders 175-176
    - Dr. Ernst Hauswedell (Firm), 1956-63 (Box 5, Folder 209)
      Includes invoice
    - Drew University. Georges Simenon Center, 1982-87 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - Droemer Knaur, 1987-88 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - Droemersche Verlagsanstalt, 1963 Jul (Box 5, Folder 212)
      See also: Thorwald, Jürgen, Box 42, folder 1316
    - Droste Verlag und Druckerei, 1955-62 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Du, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - Dufner, Max, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - Duggan, Alfred Leo, 1959-60 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Du Pontavice, Anne, 1990-91, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - Durand, J. P., 1958 Nov 30 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Du Sautoy, Peter, 1960-93 (Box 5, Folder 219-220)
      See also: Faber and Faber, Box 6, folders 259-262
    - "E" General, 1960-91 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Eastman, Ann; Eastman, Arthur, 1988, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - Ebon, Martin, 1985 Sep 25 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - Eco, Umberto, 1982-93 (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - Ediciones Alfaguara, 1982 Sep 29 (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - Editions Bernard Grasset, 1961-67, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Editions du Seuil, 1960-84 (Box 5, Folder 227-229)
    - Éditions Stock, 1984-87, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 230)
    - Editorial Seix Barral, 1960-67 (Box 5, Folder 231-232)
    - Editor's Dinner Group, 1981-90, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 233)
    - Edizioni il Polifilo, 1961-65 (Box 5, Folder 234-235)
    - Edmunds, John, 1959 Jun 11 (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - Edschmid, Kasimir, 1961-63 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - Edwards, Colin D., 1986 (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - Ehrlich, Leonard H.; Ehrlich, Edith, 1967-94 (Box 5, Folder 239-240)
      Includes letters from Ehrlich to Michael Ermarth
    - Ehrmann, Henry [Walter?], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 241)
    - Einaudi, Giulio, 1989 Jan 20 (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - Eisenreich, Herbert, 1959-63 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1960 (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - Ellermann, Heinrich, 1961-62 (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - Ellmann, Richard, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - Enzenberger, Hans Magnus, 1962-64 (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - Epstein, Barbara, 1977 May 1 (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - Eranos Conference, 1950-58, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 249)
    - Eridanos Press, Inc., 1988 Apr 7 (Box 5, Folder 250)
    - Ermarth, Michael, 1984-93 (Box 5, Folder 251)
      See also: Ehrlich, Leonard H., Box 5, folders 239-240, and University of Chicago Press, Box 43, folder 1342
    - Ernst, Cane, Berner & Gitlin, 1962-75 (Box 5, Folder 252)
      See also: Cane, Melville, Box 3, folders 131-133
    - Ervin, Jean; Ervin, John, 1972 Feb (Box 5, Folder 253)
    - Ettinger, Elzbieta, 1991-93 (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - Eugen Diederichs Verlag, 1961, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - "F" General, 1960-89, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 256)
    - F. A. Brockhaus (Firm), 1963-65 (Box 6, Folder 257)
    - F. A. Herbig, 1962 Apr (Box 6, Folder 258)
    - Faber and Faber, 1959-81 (Box 6, Folder 259-262)
      Includes copies of third-party correspondence
      See also: Du Sautoy, Peter, Box 5, folders 219-220
    - Faber du Faur, Kurt von, 1941-63, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 263-269)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, 1953 Jul (Box 6, Folder 270)
    - Farau, Alfred, 1968-70 (Box 6, Folder 271)
    - Farrer, David, 1976 Jun 30 (Box 6, Folder 272)
    - Fayard (Firm), 1984-85 (Box 6, Folder 273)
    - Feltrinelli editore, 1959-88, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 274-275)
      See also: Third-Party Correspondence, Box 46, folder 1481
    - Fermi, Laura, 1966-67 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    - Fetter, Victoria L., 1982 (Box 6, Folder 277)
    - Fiedler, Leonhard M., 1984 Mar 6 (Box 6, Folder 278)
    - Fischer, Casa, 1977-86 (Box 6, Folder 279)
    - Fischer, Heinrich, 1959, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 280)
    - Fischer, Peter Thomas, 1985-86 (Box 6, Folder 281)
      Includes copy of letter to Fischer from Milan Dubrovic
    - Fish, Richardson & Neave, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 282)
    - Fisher, Elizabeth, 1970-81, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 283-285)
    - Fittko, Lisa, 1982-83 (Box 6, Folder 286)
    - Fjord Press, 1982-85 (Box 7, Folder 287)
    - Flammarion (Firm), 1957-85 (Box 7, Folder 288)
    - Flexner, Mrs. James Thomas, 1974 Mar 14 (Box 7, Folder 289)
    - Fondazione Giovanni Agnelli, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 290)
    - Formations, 1983 Sep 2 (Box 7, Folder 291)
    - Forvm, 1964 Apr 7 (Box 7, Folder 292)
    - Frances G. Wickes Foundation, 1968-73 (Box 7, Folder 293)
    - Francis Edwards (Firm), 1962-63 (Box 7, Folder 294)
    - Franke, Herbert, 1961-64 (Box 7, Folder 295)
    - Franz J. Horch Associates, 1961-65 (Box 7, Folder 296)
    - Fraser, Dana R., 1968 (Box 7, Folder 296a)
    - Frechtman, Bernard, 1964-67 (Box 7, Folder 297)
    - Fries, Ulrich, 1984-94, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 298)
    - Frisch, Karl von, 1962-80 (Box 7, Folder 299-305)
    - Frisch, Max, 1972-91, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 306-308)
      Includes third-party correspondence, letter from Frisch to Donald Barthelme, and enclosures
    - Frisch, Otto von, 1963-82, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 309)
    - Fritz, [Kurt von?], 1961 Jun 20 (Box 7, Folder 310)
    - Fröbe-Kapteyn, Olga
      See: Eranos Conference, Box 5, folder 249
    - Fuchs, Albert, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 311)
    - Fulbright, J. William (James William), 1985 Jul 31 (Box 7, Folder 312)
    - "G" General, 1959-88 (Box 7, Folder 313)
    - Galantière, Lewis, 1960-61, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 314)
    - Galligan, Edward L., 1967 Nov (Box 7, Folder 315)
    - Gallimard (Firm), 1948-87 (Box 7, Folder 316-318)
      See also: Sasaki, Ruth Fuller, Box 38, folder 1170
    - Gamer, Eleanor
      See: Sasaki, Ruth Fuller, Box 38, folder 1171
    - Ganymed Press, 1962-63 (Box 7, Folder 319)
    - Garzanti (Firm), 1959-87 (Box 7, Folder 320)
    - Gebr. Mann Verlag, 1959-63 (Box 7, Folder 321)
    - [Gebsattel, Victor Emil, Freiherr von], 1963, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 322)
    - Geisenheyner & Crone, 1960-63 (Box 7, Folder 323-324)
    - Gemming, Klaus, 1960-62 (Box 8, Folder 325)
    - Georges Borchardt Inc., 1982-86 (Box 8, Folder 326)
      See also: Third-Party Correspondence, Box 46, folder 1474
    - Germany (West). Generalkonsulat, 1980-90 (Box 8, Folder 327)
    - Ghanem, Ali, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 328)
    - Gidal, Sonia, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 329)
    - Gidal, Tim, 1967 Apr 30 (Box 8, Folder 330)
    - Giedion-Welcker, Carola, 1961-62 (Box 8, Folder 331)
    - Gissen, Max, 1953-71, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 332)
    - Göbel, Wolfram, 1970-77, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 333)
    - Goethe House New York, 1975-92 (Box 8, Folder 334)
    - Goethe Institute Boston, 1982 Dec 8 (Box 8, Folder 335)
    - Goethe-Institut (Munich, Germany), 1984-85 (Box 8, Folder 336)
    - Gombrich, E. H. (Ernst Hans), 1962 (Box 8, Folder 337)
    - Gombrich, Lisbeth, 1973, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 338)
    - Goodheart, Pat, 1986, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 339)
    - Goodman, William B., 1982-94 (Box 8, Folder 340-341)
      Includes plan for Prague in Black and Gold by Peter Demetz
    - Göpfert, Herbert [Georg], 1960-77 (Box 8, Folder 342)
    - Görres, Ida Friederike, 1960 Mar 9 (Box 8, Folder 343)
    - Gough, Michael, 1959 Jul 16 (Box 8, Folder 344)
    - Grambow, Jürgen, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 345)
    - Graphische Kunstanstalt Ganymed, 1928 Jan (Box 8, Folder 346)
    - Grass, Günter, 1959-69 (Box 8, Folder 347-354)
    - Grass, Günter, 1970-93, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 355-361)
    - Green, Julien, 1960-78, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 362-364)
    - Greenburger, Sanford Jerome, 1963-67 (Box 9, Folder 365)
    - Gregory, Horace, 1965 Apr (Box 9, Folder 366)
    - Greve, Ludwig, 1983-91, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 367)
    - Grol, Lini R., 1969 May 9 (Box 9, Folder 368)
    - Gross, Gerald, 1959-87, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 369)
      See also: Oz, Amos, Box 32, folder 984 and Pantheon Books, Boxes 33-34, folders 994-1025
    - Grove Press, 1960, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 370)
    - Guest, Barbara, 1985-86 (Box 9, Folder 371)
    - Guggenheim, Felix, 1961-63 (Box 9, Folder 372)
    - Gustafson, Ralph, 1981 Oct 30 (Box 9, Folder 373)
    - Gustav Kiepenheuer Bühnenvertriebs GMBH, 1965-67 (Box 9, Folder 374)
    - Guterman, Norbert, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 375)
    - Gyldendal boghandel, 1960-88, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 376)
    - "H" General, 1957-92, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 377)
    - H. Goverts Verlag, 1960-67 (Box 9, Folder 378)
    - Hackman, William R., 1983-85 (Box 9, Folder 379)
    - Hadas, Moses, 1964-66 (Box 9, Folder 380)
    - Haeften, Barbara von, 1986 Jul 6 (Box 9, Folder 381)
    - Hagenau, Gerda, 1961-70 (Box 10, Folder 382)
    - Haggard-Leirens, Virginia, 1982-83, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 383)
    - Hahn, L. Albert, 1959-60 (Box 10, Folder 384)
    - Hahn, Nora, 1959-70, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 385)
    - Haines, Charles, 1964-65 (Box 10, Folder 386)
    - Halman, Talât [Sait], 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 387)
    - Hallig, Christian, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 388)
    - Hamburger, Michael, 1961-85, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 389)
    - Hamish Hamilton Ltd., 1962-82 (Box 10, Folder 390)
    - Handelsman, Norman R., 1967-68 (Box 10, Folder 391)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1961-62 (Box 10, Folder 392-399)
      See also: Jovanovich, William, Boxes 19-21, folders 621-650
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 400-403)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1962-63 (Box 11, Folder 404-411)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 412-419)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1963-65 (Box 12, Folder 420-427)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1965-68 (Box 12, Folder 428-435)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1968-73 (Box 13, Folder 436-443)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1973-93, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 444-451)
    - Harenberg (Firm), 1979 Jul 1 (Box 13, Folder 452)
    - Harington, Donald, 1984-92, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 453-456)
      Includes letter to Harington from Jack Butler
    - Harington, Kim, 1989 Jul (Box 14, Folder 457)
    - Harman, Mark, 1984-89 (Box 14, Folder 458)
    - Harmon, Lily, 1986 Jan (Box 14, Folder 459)
    - Harper's, 1978 Jan 10 (Box 14, Folder 460)
    - Harper's Bazaar, 1953, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 461)
    - Hartman, Frank R., 1980 (Box 14, Folder 462)
    - Hausenstein, Margot, 1966, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 463)
    - Harvard University. Board of Overseers, 1979-81, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 464)
    - Harvard University. Center for European Studies, 1982 Dec 15 (Box 14, Folder 465)
    - Harvard University. Press, 1951-93 (Box 14, Folder 466)
    - Harvill Press Ltd., 1957-61 (Box 14, Folder 467-474)
      Includes enclosures and copies of third-party correspondence with John McEwen, Martin Turnell, Joy Adamson, Thomas Mertin, Adrian House, Bryher, and others
    - Harvill Press Ltd., 1961-65 (Box 14, Folder 475-482)
    - Harvill Press Ltd., 1965-69 (Box 15, Folder 483-490)
    - Harvill Press Ltd., 1970-73 (Box 15, Folder 491-498)
    - Harvill Press Ltd., 1973-76 (Box 15, Folder 499-502)
    - Harvill Press Ltd., 1976-83, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 503-506)
    - Hassan, Sana, 1988-94, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 507)
    - Haydn, Hiram, 1959 Jun (Box 16, Folder 508)
    - Hayes, Helen, 1975 May 3 (Box 16, Folder 509)
      Includes third-party correspondence and manuscript, "His Eminence and his Honor"
      See also: Loos, Anita, Box 25, folder 771
    - Hayward, John, 1954, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 510)
    - Hayward, Max, 1959-79, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 511-515)
      Includes reader report on Boris Pasternak
    - Heart Corporation, 1959 Aug (Box 16, Folder 516)
    - Heddenhausen, ----, 1948 Jun (Box 16, Folder 517)
    - Hegner, Jakob, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 518)
    - Heilbut, Anthony, 1983 May 13 (Box 16, Folder 519)
    - Heimann, Fritz, 1948, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 520)
    - Hein, Ruth, 1959-82 (Box 16, Folder 521)
    - Heinemann (Firm), 1960, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 522)
    - Helbig-Kehrer, Otti, 1960-61 (Box 16, Folder 523)
    - Heise, Carl Georg, 1958-66 (Box 16, Folder 524)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 1959 Mar 23 (Box 16, Folder 525)
      Carbon to Hemingway from Kurt Wolff
    - Henry, Robert Lee, 1960, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 526)
    - Hertog, Susan, 1986 Nov (Box 16, Folder 527)
    - Hesse, Heiner, 1971-72 (Box 16, Folder 528)
    - Hesse, Hermann; Hesse, Ninon, 1961-63 (Box 16, Folder 529)
    - Hessler, Jochem, 1986-87, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 530)
    - Heurch, Jan van, 1983-84, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 531)
    - Heydt, Erich, 1982-88 (Box 16, Folder 532-533)
    - Hill, Claude, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 534)
    - Hiller, Helmut, 1961 May 7 (Box 16, Folder 535)
    - Hills, Anna, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 536)
    - Hinderer, Walter